ON THE LINE
Hello, security.
May I take a look in your baby carriage?
哈囉 我是保全 可以看一下你的嬰兒推車嗎
Hello.
哈囉
Nice trick, aluminium foil.
不錯嘛 錫箔紙
But did you really think
detectors were the only protection?
但你以為只要躲過偵測器就夠了嗎
My boyfriend and I are unemployed.
我跟我男朋友都失業了
And we have a baby.
但是我們有小孩
I'm sorry to hear that.
我很抱歉
But I need to see an ID.
但是我需要看你的身分證
Can't you bend the rules?
你可以這一次通融一下嗎?
I've never done it before.
我從來沒有這樣過
And it won't happen again.
以後也絕對不會再發生了
Listen...
聽著
If you can't identify yourself...
如果你不出示身分證
If you can't identify yourself,
I'll have to report you.
如果你不出示身分證
我必須要向上呈報
Just a moment, please.
請等一下
I told you to sit down.
- Get your hands off of me!
我叫你坐下
-放開你的手
What's wrong?
- Everything under control.
怎麼了
-一切都在控制中
Mr. Sheriff won't even
give me a glass of water.
Mr. Sheriff連水都不給我
You better sit down now, smart-ass!
你最好放聰明點給我坐下
Sven, I'll take care of this.
Sven, 這交給我吧
Everything alright?
沒事吧?
Please excuse my colleague.
原諒我同事
Come with me, please.
請跟我來
I loved reading it.
我超喜歡這一本
I don't know how she does it.
What an observer! - Amazing.
我不知道她怎麼辦到的 好一個觀察家
太神奇了
Unbelievable.
不可思議
Thanks.
- Goodbye.
謝謝
-再見
Hello.
- Hello, Sarah.
哈囉
-哈囉 沙拉
Busy?
- Not really.
忙嗎
-還好
Shall I wrap it?
要包起來嗎
No, it's for me.
不用 這是我自己要看的
Excuse me. Sarah...
不好意思 沙拉
Can you help me?
My register's gone crazy again. - OK.
我的收銀機又壞了
你可以幫我看一下嗎
-好的
Can you take over?
你可以接手嗎
Excuse me.
不好意思
Hello, Rolf!
哈囉 羅夫
Good choice.
選得好
22.90, please.
拜託
Sven...
沙文
What was with you this afternoon...?
你今天下午怎麼了
Are you defending them?
They were professionals.
你是在替它們辯護嗎
他們是專業扒手
We're the professionals.
我們才是專業的
No matter...
- They took everything in sight. Remember?
無所謂
-他們一瞬間就扒走了 記得嗎
If someone wants a glass of water,
you can't refuse that.
但如果有人要杯水 你還是不能不給
Why don't you buy them flowers, too?
- Sven...
那你要不要還買花給他們啊
-沙文...
I tried to help you.
我試著想幫你
Know what? Take care of your shit alone.
知道嗎?管好你自己的事就好
What? You're unbelievable!
你真是不可理喻
Can't you pull yourself together for once?
你難道不能振作一點嗎
Silly me was even
looking forward to seeing you.
我真是蠢 還希望可以見到你
Shit!
狗屎
Nice girlfriend.
- Yeah, e0x-girlfriend.
女朋友不錯嘛
-對 前女友
What a loser.
真是個失敗者
He gave you the finger.
他對你比中指
Yeah! ?Come on, d0o what you did
with Mario last week.
是嘛 快點 再做一次你上禮拜對馬力歐做的事
I will, but film it, OK?
好 幫我錄下來
All right, hold on.
好啊 等一下
OK, I'm recording.
好了 我在錄了
Hello!
哈囉
Go to your friends.
- Console him, he's sad!
去你找你朋友
- 安慰他一下他很傷心
Oh, h0is aching heart!
Console him, that's it. - Show me.
喔 受傷的心
去安慰他啦 沒錯 就是這樣
- 我看看
Hello.
哈囉
Go over there... - What?
Do you think I'm afraid? Don't touch me.
去那邊 -甚麼
你以為我怕你嗎 不要碰我
What do you want? Come on.
你要幹嘛? 來啊
What? Piss off, man.
甚麼? 滾遠點老兄
Check it out.
你看看
What the fuck?
Think you can push me around?
幹甚麼?
你憑甚麼推我
Try that with me!
在對我做一次看看
Where are you going?
你要去哪
Now you're scared.
- Calm down.
現在你害怕了吧
-冷靜點
What do you want?
- Shut up or I'll smash your face!
你要甚麼
-閉嘴 不然我就打爆你的臉
Now you're in trouble!
你現在麻煩大了!
Of course not.
當然不
Can't even leave home anymore.
現在連出門都不行了
Just think,
你看
I'm always alone in the train
on the last stops. - Enjoy your meals.
每次到最後幾站我都是一個人
-請享用
Such terrible stories
in the newspaper every day!
這種事報紙裡面天天都有
Kids. If they get bored nowadays, bang!
這些不良少年 哪天它們無聊了 碰!
What happened?
- Haven't you heard?
發生甚麼事
-你沒聽說嗎?
The guy who got beaten to death.
有的男的昨晚被打死了
Where?
- In the subway last night.
在哪
-在地鐵上
Sarah's brother.
- What?
沙拉的哥哥
-甚麼?
The German bookshop clerk.
You know her.
那個德國書店店員
你知道的
Did they say why?
他們有說為什麼嗎?
Like I said, v0iolent kids.
像我說的 一群惡少
They left him there. Poor Sarah...
他們把他丟下就跑了 可憐的沙拉
Rolf?
Don't you take that same line?
你不是搭同一條線嗎?
Aren't there any people around at that hour?
難道那時候沒有別人在附近嗎?
I don't know.
我沒有注意
Probably.
有許有吧
#YOUTH VIOLENCE
Three young suspects have been caught.
三名年輕嫌犯被捕
#According to police,
根據警方
#they're claiming innocence,
saying it was an accident.
他們宣稱無罪 只是一場意外
#The victim was found half an hour later.
嫌犯在一個半小時後被找到
#He died on the way to hospital.
受害人在送醫途中不治
What's this?
這是甚麼
Give me the camera and come with me.
攝影機交出來並跟我走
My backpack.
在我的背包
Keep on babbling.
- Let go of me!
繼續說
-放開我
You're out of line. I'll report you.
你太超過了 我要舉發你
Yeah? Go ahead.
Wanna hit me in the face, too?
是嗎? 去啊
要不要順便打我一拳
Are you nuts?
你神經病
It's really crazy down there.
下面一片混亂
Got a light?
有火嗎?
Thanks.
謝謝
I hope I didn't take your spot.
我希望我沒有搶了你的地盤
No.
不
There's plenty of space up here.
這裡空間多的是
Why is your German so good?
為什麼你們德國人人都這麼好
I used to live in Germany.
我以前住在德國
Karstadt.
(German department store)
Can I ask you something?
我可以麻煩你一件事嗎
Yeah, sure.
當然
We live in the same district
and take the same train.
我們住在同一區 又搭同一條線的火車
Yes, I...
- We're doing inventories, I was wondering
是
-我們最近在做盤點 所以我在想
if you could take the train with me.
如果你可以跟我一起搭車
Only if you're working late too.
當然如果你也很晚下班的話
On what exactly do you focus?
你是指?
I mean at work.
我是說工作的時候
How do you spot shoplifters?
你怎麼找出那些是扒手
Hard to say. Most are repeat offenders.
很難說 但有些是重複犯案
"Regulars."
慣竊
And the others?
那其他人呢?
Are there any... signs?
有甚麼徵兆嗎?
Their eyes.
他們的眼睛
I mostly watch their eyes.
我通常會看眼睛
Eyes reveal everything.
眼睛透露一切
The guy with the beard, for example.
比如說那個留鬍子那男的
Look at his eyes. Something's wrong.
看他的眼睛有些不對勁
Do you think so?
你覺得呢
Ticket control. Show all tickets, please.
查票 請出示車票
It won't be easy getting over this.
要忘掉這些不容易
When my daughter's hamster died,
I know, that was just an animal,
當我女兒的倉鼠死掉的時候
我知道只是動物
but it took her months!
但也養了好幾個月
Now something like this,
I can't even imagine it.
像沙拉這樣的事 我連想都不敢想
Still, s0he's pretty.
不過她還是很漂亮
I'd know how to console her.
我知道該怎樣安慰她
Don't you...
難道你
Don't you have any respect at all?
難道你不能尊重一點嗎
Are you overworked?
你工作壓力太大了嗎
Nonsense.
胡說
Is something wrong?
還是有甚麼事?
I'm fine!
我很好
Hello.
- Hello.
哈囉
-哈囉
I wanted to thank you for yesterday.
我想要為昨天的事謝謝你
You don't need to.
- Yes, I do.
你不需要
-不 我堅持
Thanks again.
還是謝謝你
You can zoom with this.
你可以用這個放大
Look at that guy.
看那個男的
He's up to something.
他有點怪怪的
No, I know him.
不 我知道他
He comes everyday and sprays himself.
他每天都來噴香水
Sometimes he goes
to the deli for free samples.
有時候他會到熟食區拿試吃
Maybe I should, too.
或許我也該這麼做
My God, you can really see everything.
天啊 你這裡甚麼都看的到
Sarah, I...
- Look, there he is again.
沙拉 我....
-你看 他又出現了
Unbelievable.
- Yeah.
不可置信
-對啊
See?
你看吧
He's really digging in.
他真的很投入
Sorry, what were you saying?
對不起 你剛剛說甚麼
Just, nothing.
喔沒事
Well, I've got to go.
那麼我該走了
But I want to repay you for yesterday.
但我想為昨天的事報答你
That's not necessary.
沒有這必要
Really.
真的
Can I make a suggestion?
I'd play the four to set up the cue ball...
我可以建議你嗎
我打四號球把白球一到那邊....
You know...
你知道
Do what you want.
I'll take the red one.
- OK.
我要打紅色那顆
-好吧
Not bad.
不錯嘛
It feels good to get out again.
能逃出來的感覺真好
My colleagues are pretty annoying
at the moment.
我同事最近真的蠻煩的
They mean well.
他們是好意
Yes, I know.
我知道
But...
但是
nobody acts normal around me anymore.
我身邊的人都變得好刻意
I'm sorry, too.
我也很抱歉
About your brother.
關於你哥哥
Thanks.
謝謝
It's your turn.
換你了
What's up? Aren't we playing?
- Yes.
甚麼了? 不是在玩嗎
- 恩
Go!
開始吧
Next round's on the loser.
輸的人請下一盤
Want another drink?
要再來一杯嗎
How about coffee instead?
還是要咖啡?
Shit!
狗屎
Bloody hell.
他媽的
Are you alright?
- Damn it.
你還好嗎?
-該死
Wait.
等等
Just a sec.
等一下下
It'll pass.
會過去的
Nothing will pass.
不會過去
What do you know?
你怎麼知道
You don't have a clue.
你甚麼都不懂
Do you know what it's like
to wake up every morning
你知道那種每天早上起來
knowing everything would be different
if I hadn't been so damn stubborn.
知道如果我沒有這麼固執一切都會不一樣 是甚麼感覺嗎
All he wanted was my help.
他只是要我幫他
Stop it.
不要再說了
I shouldn't have left him alone.
我不應該留他一個人在那裏
It was an accident.
那只是個意外
It's not your fault.
不是你的錯
Why are you doing all this?
你這一切是為什麼?
I...
我
Wait.
等等
Sorry, I...
對不起 我
I don't know what...
我不知道
No, I'm the one who's sorry.
不 我才是那個要抱歉的人
Subtitling by SUBS Hamburg
Matthew Way